Okay, I'm now called to order the regular meeting of the Miami City Council for Tuesday, February 21st.
Public input and unscheduled personal chances at none. Action items, the asset we approve items for five and four and five.
So we have to pull some things out here.
We have some claims that we would ask that they would be pulled out with the sake of Councilman Williams and Councilman Sunberg.
They called each, they would like to pull out of that claim list.
So we need to call those out specifically.
Yes.
Okay.
I don't have those.
Can you guys help me out?
So that line on there.
Just let me just say who it's to.
Okay, so.
Okay, so in these claims, we're pulling up the payment for lease concrete.
That will be voted on a delay time in the amount of 37,472 dollars.
And then for the other claim that we can pull out is to program Williams for training for the young.
We have a very seven dollars in the youth.
But so individually, after we go over the dollar.
Everything, but those two.
We won't be voting on those two.
I don't have to be voting on the next council.
They can be voted on.
Oh, individually, understood.
Okay.
So now we are going to vote on the on the on the four to five, excluding the two items.
We just call that.
I get a motion.
Motion.
Second.
So.
But first.
Williams.
He's back.
Now I need a motion to approve payments.
You meet concrete in the amount of 37,342 dollars.
Motion.
Second.
And this is our budget amendment that we talked about in, and I'm sorry, I apologize
Mr. Schuillon.
Number six.
Shanna Dewan is here if she gives a presentation from me.
Good evening. How are you folks tonight? It's always a pleasure to come speak to the council as you know
Part of our con your contract with maids requires me to be here once a quarter, and so tonight. I'm here to update you and
I've got some information. I want to share with you. I don't know if you had a chance to look in your packets
To see the information that's in there, but
The first thing I want to touch on is just seeing this slide before it's our strategic initiatives for 23 and
Really, I want you to focus on these three because what we're going to talk about is some survey results
So mech economic survey results tonight. I want you to see how they relate to three of our key strategic initiatives
And that's a business retention and expansion workforce development and recruitment of new business
This survey was actually done by our friends at the Mokan partnership. So if you don't know what the Mokan partnership is
They basically it's a it's a regional seven county region economic development organization
It's kind of like a grand gateway type organization and it focuses on Southeast Kansas Southwest Missouri and then us here out of a county here in Oklahoma
And so they did this survey at the end of 22
They surveyed roughly 15,000 employers in the seven region area that they covered and
The survey focus primarily on community business and work or trends and the purpose was to take that information and give it back to those businesses in industry
To try to figure out and give them some tools that may help them in overcoming some of the economic challenges that
They're facing obviously we will the workforce needs in this community are well documented
So we're going to go on with some of those surveys
Today because I think you're going to find them interesting because these are the kind of tools that I look at and other economic development
Professions look at when we're talking about economic development in primarily a big focus of what made
Is going to be working on in the coming months is business retention and expansion and work force development
So they didn't survey so here were some of the top excuse me take away is from the survey first of all
Finding qualified employees and returning retaining current workers is considered to be among the top challenges facing businesses in the industry
Right now
We just did a job fair on February 9 and
There were
He ended up all of the jobs that were potentially available that day. There were so for 150 jobs
There were 70 people
Think that's right
Now the win 70 week we get the list